Vivian Chen

vivianc206@gmail.com | 917.353.2308 | Github | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Data analyst with 2+ years of experience in creating and aggregating data, generating visualizations, and writing documentation. Strong interests in understanding urban infrastructure patterns, public transportation accessibility, and intuitive design. Seeking opportunities to apply and enhance data mining and programming skills to create solutions for real-life applications, urban issues, and company efficiency.

EDUCATION AND HONORS

NYU Center for Urban Science and Progress

08/2019 - Present

Master of Science in Applied Urban Science and Informatics

- Relevant Coursework: Urban Spatial Analytics; Civic Analytics and Urban Intelligence; Applied Data Science; Principles of Urban Informatics; Data Governance Ethics and Privacy
- Member of the Applied Urban Science Group (AUSG)

Macaulay Honors College at Hunter College (CUNY)

New York, NY

GPA: 3.701

Bachelor of Arts in Geographical Information Science

08/2015 - 06/2019

- Minors in Computer Science and Media Studies
- Member of Gamma Theta Upsilon (GTU)

SKILLS

- Coding Languages and Database Applications: Python, SQL, VBA, Microsoft Access
- GIS and Data Visualization Software: ArcMap, ArcCatalog, QGIS, Carto
- Design: HTML, CSS, Adobe (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign)
- Languages: English (native), Mandarin (conversational), Cantonese (conversational), French (basic)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Barnard College, Empirical Reasoning Center

08/2019 - Present

Teaching Assistant

- Support Prof. Alisa Rod in the lab section of the GIS Methods course through guiding students on using GIS
- Grade weekly labs and hold office hours for students

New York City Department of Transportation

GIS College Aide

03/2018 – Present

- Working within the Asset Management Unit to create, maintain, and update various geo-databases through customized scripts using Python, SQL, and VBA
- Using ArcMap, ArcCatalog, and QGIS to create and edit maps and metadata of NYC DOT assets
- Create dashboards using MS Excel and MS Access for data visualization and projection analysis
- Through MS Access, designed a database to track seating arrangements for all DOT floors within the 55
 Water St. building to streamline the agency's emergency preparedness procedures; used MS Project for
 progress tracking

The Graduate Center, City University of New York

Research Intern

08/2017 - 01/2019

• Conducted research and created an interactive map to visualize neo-antique sites via CARTO for Dr. Elizabeth Macaulay-Lewis' publication: <u>Classical New York Discovering Greece and Rome in Gotham</u>

American Geographical Society

Scholar Intern

09/2016 - 12/2016

- Maintained and updated AGS blogging sites, <u>UBIQUE</u> and <u>Connect2Conserve</u>, and interviewed companies and non-profit organizations for weekly Spotlight articles
- Prepared for the annual Fall Symposium, Geography 2050 by creating graphics for promotional items, advertising on social media, and working on-site to ensure a smooth run-of-the-show